Finding Aid for the Yvar Mikhashoff Collection of Audio Cassettes, 1967-1993
State University of New York at Buffalo. Music Library
- Commercial cassettes without Mikhashoff as performer or composer, 1967-1993, III.; Box 29-31
  Contains 115 commercially-released cassettes. The contents are split between standard classical repertoire, contemporary music, and non-Western music. The link above is provided to view the contents of all the boxes.
  - Bach - Janover, 38 audio cassettes (Box 29)
  - Janover - Prokofiev, 38 audio cassettes (Box 30)
  - Prokofiev - Wolman, 39 audio cassettes (Box 31)
Search Terms
The following terms have been used to index the description of this collection in the Library's online catalog.
Subjects
Mikhashoff, Yvar, 1941-1993 -- Archives; Music--20th century; Piano music
Genres
audiocassettes; sound recordings; musical performances
Associated Material
Index to composers and performers in the collection
Composer index, with references to cassette numbers
Adams, John 169
Albéniz, Isaac 53
Antheil, George 62, 136
Austin, Larry 205
Barber, Samuel 37, 88, 109
Bartók, Béla 41, 207
Beethoven, Ludwig van 115
Benjamin, T. 220
Bennett, Richard Bennett 175
Berg, Alban 34
Berio, Luciano 16, 39
Berkman, Robert 19, 47, 129
Bernstein, Leonard 140, 144
Biscardi, Chester 17, 129
Bloch, Ernest 149
Bohmler, Craig 48
Bolcom, William 19, 175
Boone, Charles 48
Boulez, Pierre 21
Brahms, Johannes 45
Brant, Henry 22, 23, 138, 139, 233
Braxton, Anthony 163
Brecht, George 232
Brel, Jacques 214
Brown, Earle 108
Bussotti, Sylvano 24, 26,-28, 93, 94, 232
Cage, John 8, 25, 19, 41, 42, 48, 86, 91, 108, 142, 154, 176, 193, 197, 199, 208, 219, 232
Carter, Elliott 201
Casella, Alfredo 30
Chadabe, Joel 174
Cherney, Brian 233
Chopin, Frédéric 207
Chowning, John 161
Cohen, T. 51
Confrey, Zez 148
Constanten, Henry 8, 143
Copland, Aaron 37, 41, 44, 54, 73, 74, 88, 90, 135, 149
Corigliano, John 11
Cowell, Henry 14, 41, 108, 143, 193, 209
Crawford, Ruth 140
Crumb, George 19, 150
Curran, Alvin 24, 25, 48, 56, 57, 59, 86, 89, 90, 143, 174, 176, 177, 193, 233
Davidovsky, Mario 59, 108, 120, 149
Debussy, Claude 53, 110, 182, 207, 208
Donatoni, Franco 87
Dowland, John 45
Druckman, Jacob 2, 158
Duckworth, William 25, 48, 129, 174
Dutillieux, Henri 61
Dvorák, Antonin 1
Eisler, Hanns 13, 31
Falla, Manuel de 1
Felder, David 10, 91, 200
Feldman, Morton 4, 5, 41, 63, 64, 91, 108, 142, 168, 176, 193
Feliciano, Jose 8
Fennimore, Joseph 19, 62, 207
Ferneyhough, Brian 65
Field, Richard 121
Finney, Ross Lee 8, 66, 140
Foss, Lukas 14, 39, 48, 67, 68, 69, 91, 106, 120, 129, 143, 144, 174, 177, 178, 193, 209
Fricker, P. Racine 43
Gade, Jacob 214
Genge, Anthony 129, 175
Gerhard, Roberto 70
Gershwin, George 30, 138
Gilman, Lawrence 209
Glanville-Hicks, Peggy 148
Glass, Philip 8, 19, 25, 89, 106, 107, 110, 140, 142
Gould, Morton 90, 139
Grainger, Percy 72, 88, 139, 141
Grieg, Edvard 88
Griffes, Charles 136, 176
Hachimura, Yoshio 16
Harris, Roy 37, 148
Harrison, Lou 8, 19, 142, 144
Hartmann, Thomas de 24
Hauer, Josef Matthias 36
Hill, Jackson 50, 129, 174, 175
Hiller, Lejaren 41, 64, 75, 76, 77
Hindemith, Paul 1, 41
Hopkins, John 85
Honegger, Arthur 30
Hovhaness, Alan 136, 144, 178
Hoyland, Vic 87
Ince, Kamran 149
Ives, Charles 1, 7, 11, 36, 95, 154, 185
Janácek, Leoš 9
Johnson, Hunter 37, 220
Johnson, Tom 19, 174
Jolas, Betsy 107
Kondo, Jo 175
Krenek, Ernst 98, 149, 210, 214, 219
Lang, David 88
Lehrer, Tom 219
Lieberson, Peter 169
Ligeti, György 161
Liszt, Franz 25, 101, 102, 103, 104, 105, 114, 115
Loomis, Harvey Worthington 209
Luening, Otto 138, 219
Mahler, Gustav 7
Martinu, Bohuslav 50
Martland, Steve 113
Mason, Benedict 87
MacDowell, Edward 86, 88
Merdella, Culderico 116
Messiaen, Olivier 39, 69, 158
Mikhashoff, Yvar 14, 41, 43, 50, 89, 121, 122, 123, 124, 125, 126, 203, 209, 219, 220
Milhaud, Darius 13, 183
Monk, Meredith 212
Montague, Stephen 151, 152
Moran, Robert 8, 19, 142
Morley, Thomas 45
Mozart, Wolfgang Amadeus 44, 50
Munoz, O. 153
Mussorgsky, Modest 1
Nancarrow, Conlon 19, 24, 25, 62, 67, 89-91, 129, 135, 148, 154, 160-170, 186, 194, 214, 219
Neuwirth, Gosta 209
Newell, John 156
Nichifor, Serban Alexandru 174
Nolte, Roy 25
Norgaard, Bjorn 62, 120, 201
Norholm, Ib 159
Ogden, Will 209
Olsen, Poul Rovsing 201
Ornstein, Leo 90, 143, 144, 193, 201
Ortiz, William 25
Osborne, Nigel 16
Palmer, Robert 181, 182
Paulus, Stephen 149
Pender, Scott 48, 129
Perle, George 61
Porter, Cole 30
Poulenc, Francis 2, 30, 43, 114, 115
Prokofiev, Sergei 34, 189, 190
Radecke, Steven 156
Ravel, Maurice 1, 53, 191, 192
Reich, Steve 161
Revueltas, Silvestre 13
Riegger, Wallingford 90, 135, 136
Riley, Howard 14, 209
Rorem, Ned 62, 86
Rothstein, Joseph 156
Roussel, Albert 13
Ruders, Poul 9, 174 ,195
Rudhyar, Dane 19, 89, 129, 135, 174, 195
Ruggles, Carl 110, 137
Rzewski, Frederic 19, 25, 54, 86, 89, 107, 137, 159, 175, 193
Sackmann, Michael 113
Sahl, Michael 19, 25, 48, 129, 177
Satie, Erik 2, 30, 32, 41, 62, 106, 196, 197, 198, 199, 200, 208, 214, 219
Savashkan 175
Sbordoni, Alessandro 7
Scelsi, Giacinto 24, 93, 94, 168
Schoenberg, Arnold 34, 38
Schubert, Franz 114, 115
Schumann, Robert 1, 50, 114
Schwantner, Joseph C. 149
Schwartz, Elliott 25
Scriabin, Aleksandr 36
Seeger, Ruth Crawford 186
Sellars, James 37, 88, 108, 201-206
Sepos, Charles 47
Sharman, Rodney 25
Shiomi, Mieko 232
Shostakovitch, Dimitri 210
Sierra, Roberto 212
Singleton, Alvin 149
Smalley, Dennis 122
Smalley, Roger 12
Smit, Leo 41, 156
Smith 2
Stockhausen, Karlheinz 39, 211
Strauss, Richard 114, 115
Stravinsky, Igor 30, 34, 43, 62, 86, 106, 135
Takemitsu, Tori 11
Thomson, Virgil 8, 19, 37, 62, 73, 74, 143, 144, 199, 200, 214, 221-231
Trimble, Lester 45
Twining, Toby 48
Ungheresi, Uccelli 15
Vigeland, Nils 10, 19, 23, 91, 140, 156, 233, 239, 240, 241
Vivaldi, Antonio 1
Walton, William 13
Ware, Peter 248
Weber, Carl Maria von 45
Webern, Anton 34, 38
Weill, Kurt 38, 214, 219
Wolff, Christian 108, 159, 193
Wolpe, Stefan 90
Wryter, Nib 15
Xenakis, Iannis 158
Yim, Jay Allen 87
Zappa, Frank 136, 212
Zimmerman, Bernd Alois 155
Performer index, with references to cassette numbers
Adams, John (conductor) 169
Algard, Alexander (piano) 96
Almeida Ensemble 4, 5
Arditti Quartet 7, 87, 155
Armborg, Susanna (piano) 96
Austin Symphony Orchestra 101
Avery, James 65
Baird Contemporary Ensemble 13, 14
Baird Trio 240
Bjelkstam, Lotta (piano) 96
Blum, Eberhard (flute) 240
Bohmler, Craig (piano) 48
Boudler, John (percussion) 223, 224, 225, 226, 227, 228
Bouwhuis, G. 212
Buffalo Philharmonic Orchestra 10, 11, 12, 158
Cal Arts 20th Century Players 22
Casen, Petra (piano) 97
Clementi Trio Cologne 15
Dillard, Ray (drums) 48
Eden, Viggo (piano) 97
Egerbladh, Berndt (piano) 96
Eggen, Christian (conductor) 239
Einarsdotter, Elise (piano) 96
Elfving, Hans-Goeran (piano) 97
Ensemble Köln 15
Ensemble Modern 165, 168, 169, 170
Fuller, David (harpsichord, organ) 242, 243, 244, 245
Halpin, Thomas (violin) 73, 74, 98
Heatherington, Alan (conductor) 17
Held, Barbara (flute) 240
Herr, Martha (soprano) 223, 224, 225, 226, 227, 228
Hinds, Nigel (gentleman) 155
Hoejer, Olof (piano) 96
Indiana University New Music Ensemble 10
Ishii, Ken (cello) 16
Jansson, Kerstin (piano) 97
Jones, Kathleen (clarinet) 212
Kallstrom, Sofie (piano) 96
Kase, Sonoke (piano) 97
Kettlewell, David (piano) 96
Kjersgaard, Mads (piano) 97
Krieger, Jeffrey (cello) 206
Kuehn, David (trumpet) 223, 224, 225, 226, 227, 228
Kussner, Johann (flute) 240
Loewdin, Bjarne (piano) 96
MacKay, Ronald (piano) 207
Manes, Frieda (piano) 75
Manes, Stephen (piano) 75
Mannheimer, Irene (piano) 96
Mare, Anthony de (piano) 73, 74, 212
Metzmacher, Ingo (conductor) 165, 170
Mikhashoff, (lecturer) 249
Mikhashoff, (piano) 1-14, 16- 64, 66-68, 73-76, 78, 80, 82-96, 98, 102- 205, 208- 239, 241- 48
Monk, Meredith (voice) 212
Nanor, Josef (piano) 97
New London Chamber Choir 212
Nordwalls, Eva (harpsichord) 212
Norwegian Radio Orkestra 239
Notini, Slim (piano) 96
Oppens, Ursula 16
Peress, Maurice 101
Persson, Mats (piano) 97
Platz, Robert H. P. 15
Rarick, Janet (oboe) 48
Sardikhashoff 15
Scattergood, Joanne (soprano) 203
Schaffer, Christine (piano) 48
Schilling, Anders (piano) 96
Schmidt, Paul (declamation) 102, 114
Scholz, Kristine (piano) 97
Siegel, Allan (clarinet) 98
Sjoesten, Lars (piano) 96
Smit, Leo (piano) 30
Sollberger 10
Stanislaw, Sumita (harp) 240
Stowe, Sara (soprano) 212
Straat, Anna (piano) 96
Strom, Katarina (piano) 97
Sundell, Stina (piano) 97
Takahashi, Aki (piano) 196, 197
Thomson, Virgil (narrator) 198, 199, 200
Tilles, N. (piano) 212
Twining, Toby (singer) 48
Udow, Michael (percussion) 10
Uitti, Frances-Marie (sampled Atari/EMAX) 15
Uitti, Frances-Marie (cello) 108, 237
University at Buffalo Philharmonic 17
Vapaavuori, Pekka (piano) 97
Vigeland, Nils (piano) 240
Wallgren, Jan (piano) 97
Williams, Wendy (flute) 48
Winn, Amy (flute) 48
Wood, James (conductor) 212
Wood, James (percussion) 212
Related Resources
Related Resources in the Music Library
Yvar Mikhashoff Collections
The Yvar Mikhashoff Collections contain the following separate components. Descriptions can be found at LibGuide page for the Yvar Mikhashoff archival resources at
https://research.lib.buffalo.edu/mikhashoff/archival
:
Yvar Mikhashoff Collections of Compositions, Transcriptions, Annotated Scores, Tangos, Reel to reel Recordings, Video Recordings, and Photographs
North American New Music Festival papers and recordings